Now previously we talked about finding the release point.
As we stated, the release point is essentially the point where the ball comes out of his hand.
Whether it's here, it's here, it's here, it's somewhere in this vicinity.
Now once it leaves his hand, you need to keep your eyes on the ball.
This is why in our stance we have a level head, we have both eyes pointed down at the pitcher, makes it much easier to pick up.
Why do you want to follow the ball out of his hand?
A) if you don't see the ball you can't hit the ball.
I can sit here all day with him throwing balls at me, if my eyes closed I'm not going to hit a single one.
But if I can see the ball, I have a much better chance of making contact.
What is the other thing that you get to see?
You get to see what kind of pitch is coming.
Other then what kind of pitch is coming, what else are you looking for.
You are looking for is it up, is it down, is it inside, is it outside, all these different things.
Is it way in the dirt, there is no need to swing, is it a ball, is it a strike.
You know is the umpire giving him that much room.
These are all things you can see just from following the ball.
Yes, you need to make a split second decision but that split second decision becomes a lot easier if you are watching the ball come at you instead of saying here ok, you are looking at home plate, thinking about something else.
Be looking down at the pitcher, follow the ball all the way in.
So from his release point which is here, out of his hand, you want to follow it, track it, track it, track it, all the way through contact.
And that's staying on the ball.